Hi, welcome back, everyone.
We're going to begin developments about wireless local area network application by implementing the
Ogbe status led.
He will briefly review the implementation details.
So let's take a look at our implementation overview.
We're going to create different colors by using the blood to indicate the application status.
First of all, create a function to initialize the Ogbe led settings per channel.
The GPIO used for each channel and configure the timer as well.
We'll create another function for setting the colors based on the duty cycle for each channel, each
channel being the red, green and blue channels will then create functions that set the color of the
ogbia led to be used as our application status indicators.
Finally, will test these functions in the main that see file, and we'll actually use them later to
indicate statuses such as Wi-Fi application started be server started and Wi-Fi connected.
Now, let's talk about the alleged control component of the ESB IDF.
I suggest you visit the impressive documentation here about the LED component and API reference here
you can find all you need to know about Leidy Control using the IDF.
You'll find that this component is primarily designed for lead intensity control and GWM signal generation.
So just browse through here if you can.
Also, you'll find that both high speed and low speed channels are available and there's 16 channels
total eight for high speed and eight for low speed.
Our configuration steps include three main parts, the timer and channel configurations.
And then setting it and updating the duty cycle.
So about the timer.
Each timer counts up and the bits defined determines the count number before it resets, and the frequency
determines the amount of time that it takes to count to the number.
For example, three eight bits, the count number is from zero to 255, and for ten bits it'll be from
zero to one thousand twenty three.
And the bit, number and frequency those are key members of the LED see timer config structure that
will set, including other members such as the speed mode and timer number as well.
And we'll pass this information to the LED see timer config function to set the config.
For the channel configuration, the GPIO pin that the P.W. and output signal appears on a specified
to a specific channel along with the timer will set members of the LED see channel config structure
and pass the configuration to legacy channel config.
And then next, we can create different colors by adjusting the duty cycle, which is the time duration
within the period that the GWM output signal will be high before it goes low.
And we'll do this using the LEDs set duty and LEDs update duty functions.
Now, let's briefly get into the status led colored functions that were going to create.
Arrests will have one function that sets the colored by updating to duty cycle per channel.
The red, green and blue channels and then the status function will simply call the set color function
at the duty cycle that we specified per channel, depending on the color that we want.
You can go to this link here or any other similar website.
Just search for RGV led color selection and you can customize the status LEDs as you wish.
However, for the three statuses Wi-Fi started HTTP server started and Wi-Fi connected.
I've chosen the following values.
Why if I started, is this color here?
And FTP server looks like this.
And wife, I connected look similar to this color here.
So feel free to set the colors as you wish.
Or better yet, create your own satisfactions functions as we develop the application further.
Let's briefly talk about the hardware options.
There are different flavors of our.
You can obtain the package type on a PCB or the common cathode or common A. Type.
Whichever you obtain.
Be sure to check the data sheet and verify the required resistor values, and you can make the connections
based on the GPIO as we define.
Also, if you're using the common A. a common cathode type, be sure to follow the diagram and note
the long leg difference ground versus positive voltage.
All right, so let's get started with programming in the upcoming lesson.